class QuestionModel{
  final String question;
  final List<String> options;
  final correctAnswerIndex;
  final String Solution;

  const QuestionModel({
    required this.question,
    required this.options,
    required this.correctAnswerIndex,
    required this.Solution,
  });
}


List<QuestionModel> Aerospace = [
  QuestionModel(
      question: "1. Which famous American aviator is known for being the first person to fly solo across the Atlantic Ocean?",
      options: [
        "A. Amelia Earhart",
        "B. Chuck Yeager",
        "C. Charles Lindbergh",
        "D. Neil Armstrong"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "The correct answer is C. Charles Lindbergh. Charles Lindbergh made history by completing the first solo nonstop transatlantic flight in 1927, flying from New York to Paris."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "2. What is the term for the speed at which an aircraft's forward motion overcomes the force of gravity and allows it to become airborne?",
      options: [
        "A. Lift-off velocity",
        "B. Stall speed",
        "C. Takeoff speed",
        "D. Groundspeed"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "The correct answer is C. Takeoff speed. Takeoff speed is the speed at which an aircraft generates enough lift to become airborne, typically just before the wheels leave the ground."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "3. In aerospace engineering, what is the purpose of ailerons on an aircraft's wings?",
      options: [
        "A. To control pitch",
        "B. To control roll",
        "C. To control yaw",
        "D. To control thrust"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "The correct answer is B. To control roll. Ailerons are control surfaces on an aircraft's wings that are used to control the rolling motion of the aircraft by varying lift on one wing compared to the other."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "4. What is the primary function of a gyroscope in aviation?",
      options: [
        "A. To provide in-flight entertainment",
        "B. To measure airspeed",
        "C. To provide stability and control reference",
        "D. To navigate using GPS"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "The correct answer is C. To provide stability and control reference. Gyroscopes in aviation are used to provide a stable reference for controlling an aircraft's orientation and stability."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "5. Which law of motion, formulated by Sir Isaac Newton, explains the relationship between an aircraft's motion and the forces acting upon it?",
      options: [
        "A. Newton's First Law of Motion",
        "B. Newton's Second Law of Motion",
        "C. Newton's Third Law of Motion",
        "D. Newton's Law of Universal Gravitation"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "The correct answer is C. Newton's Third Law of Motion. Newton's Third Law of Motion states that for every action, there is an equal and opposite reaction, which is fundamental in understanding aircraft motion and control."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "6. What is the purpose of the vertical stabilizer (fin) on an aircraft's tail?",
      options: [
        "A. To control pitch",
        "B. To control roll",
        "C. To control yaw",
        "D. To control thrust"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "The correct answer is C. To control yaw. The vertical stabilizer, or fin, is responsible for controlling the yawing motion of the aircraft by providing stability and directional control."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "7. In supersonic flight, what term is used to describe the shock waves generated by an aircraft moving at a speed greater than the speed of sound?",
      options: [
        "A. Sonic boom",
        "B. Jetstream",
        "C. Vortex wake",
        "D. Thermals"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "The correct answer is A. Sonic boom. A sonic boom is the shockwave produced by an object traveling through the air at a speed greater than the speed of sound, creating a loud noise."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "8. Which part of a rocket engine is responsible for expelling high-speed exhaust gases to generate thrust?",
      options: [
        "A. Nose cone",
        "B. Payload bay",
        "C. Rocket motor",
        "D. Fins"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "The correct answer is C. Rocket motor. The rocket motor is the part of a rocket engine that expels high-speed exhaust gases, creating the thrust needed for propulsion."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "9. What type of engine is commonly used in most commercial jet airliners for propulsion?",
      options: [
        "A. Turbofan engine",
        "B. Turbojet engine",
        "C. Piston engine",
        "D. Ramjet engine"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "The correct answer is A. Turbofan engine. Most commercial jet airliners are powered by turbofan engines, which are efficient and quiet compared to other engine types."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "10. Which organization is responsible for the coordination of air traffic control and navigation services in the United States?",
      options: [
        "A. NASA",
        "B. FAA (Federal Aviation Administration)",
        "C. NTSB (National Transportation Safety Board)",
        "D. DOT (Department of Transportation)"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "The correct answer is B. FAA (Federal Aviation Administration). The FAA is responsible for the regulation and oversight of civil aviation, including air traffic control and navigation services in the United States."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "11. What is the term for the highest point an aircraft can reach in its flight path before descending?",
      options: [
        "A. Apogee",
        "B. Perigee",
        "C. Altitude",
        "D. Zenith"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: "The correct answer is D. Zenith. Zenith refers to the highest point in an aircraft's flight path before it begins to descend. It is also known as the aircraft's peak or summit."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "12. In astronautics, what is the boundary that separates the Earth's atmosphere from outer space called?",
      options: [
        "A. Stratosphere",
        "B. Thermosphere",
        "C. Mesopause",
        "D. Kármán line"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: "The correct answer is D. Kármán line. The Kármán line, located at an altitude of approximately 100 kilometers (62 miles), is the internationally recognized boundary that separates Earth's atmosphere from outer space."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "13. What is the primary function of the International Space Station (ISS) in space exploration?",
      options: [
        "A. Space tourism",
        "B. Satellite deployment",
        "C. Scientific research and experimentation",
        "D. Lunar landings"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: "The correct answer is C. Scientific research and experimentation. The ISS serves as a platform for scientific research and experiments in microgravity, as well as international cooperation in space exploration."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "14. Which American space agency is responsible for the Apollo moon landing missions?",
      options: [
        "A. NASA",
        "B. SpaceX",
        "C. Blue Origin",
        "D. ESA (European Space Agency)"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "The correct answer is A. NASA. NASA, the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, was responsible for the Apollo moon landing missions, including the historic Apollo 11 mission in 1969."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "15. What does the acronym UAV stand for in aerospace technology?",
      options: [
        "A. Unmanned Aerial Vehicle",
        "B. Ultrafast Aviation Vehicle",
        "C. Universal Aerospace Vessel",
        "D. Unmanned Airborne Vehicle"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "The correct answer is A. Unmanned Aerial Vehicle. UAV stands for Unmanned Aerial Vehicle, which refers to aircraft operated without a human pilot on board."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "16. What concept in aerospace engineering is used to describe the bending of an aircraft's wings during flight?",
      options: [
        "A. Wing twist",
        "B. Flutter",
        "C. Wing loading",
        "D. Wing flex"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: "The correct answer is D. Wing flex. Wing flex is the bending or deformation of an aircraft's wings under various aerodynamic forces experienced during flight, such as turbulence and gusts."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "17. Which famous astronaut was the first person to set foot on the Moon during the Apollo 11 mission in 1969?",
      options: [
        "A. John Glenn",
        "B. Yuri Gagarin",
        "C. Buzz Aldrin",
        "D. Neil Armstrong"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: "The correct answer is D. Neil Armstrong. Neil Armstrong was the first person to set foot on the Moon during the historic Apollo 11 mission."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "18. What is the term for the aircraft's ability to maintain controlled flight during a stall condition?",
      options: [
        "A. Glide ratio",
        "B. Stall speed",
        "C. Angle of attack",
        "D. Autorotation"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: "The correct answer is A. Glide ratio. The glide ratio refers to the aircraft's ability to maintain controlled flight during a stall condition, indicating how far the aircraft can glide for a given altitude loss."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "19. What type of propulsion system is commonly used in spacecraft to maneuver in the vacuum of space?",
      options: [
        "A. Turboprop engines",
        "B. Ion thrusters",
        "C. Ramjets",
        "D. Turbofan engines"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: "The correct answer is B. Ion thrusters. Ion thrusters are commonly used in spacecraft for propulsion in the vacuum of space due to their high efficiency and low fuel consumption."
  ),

  QuestionModel(
      question: "20. In aerodynamics, what term is used to describe the flow of air around an aircraft's wing or body when it is traveling at a high speed close to the speed of sound?",
      options: [
        "A. Subsonic flow",
        "B. Hypersonic flow",
        "C. Transonic flow",
        "D. Supersonic flow"
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: "The correct answer is D. Supersonic flow. Supersonic flow occurs when an aircraft is traveling at a high speed close to or above the speed of sound, resulting in shock waves and other aerodynamic effects."
  )



];